[
    {
        "quesID": 1,
        "question": "What is the purpose of the 'ngOnInit' method in Angular?",
        "imageName": "https://play-lh.googleusercontent.com/B_tydrYsRBojzG_H8NibVu5cZtZSjL_B_387DW2ZPfMG2MXu1D2MtkWRqqz8eBowuw",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to initialize data members and make API calls.",
            "c) It is used to subscribe to Observables and handle asynchronous operations.",
            "d) It is used to create a new component instance."
        ],
        "answer": "b) It is used to initialize data members and make API calls."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 2,
        "question": "What does the 'ngFor' directive do in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to create a new component instance.",
            "b) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "c) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "d) It is used to subscribe to Observables and handle asynchronous operations."
        ],
        "answer": "c) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 3,
        "question": "Which decorator is used to define a component in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) @Module",
            "b) @Component",
            "c) @Directive",
            "d) @Injectable"
        ],
        "answer": "b) @Component"
    },
    {
        "quesID": 4,
        "question": "What is a template in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is a file that contains TypeScript code.",
            "b) It is a file that defines the structure and layout of a component's view.",
            "c) It is a service that handles HTTP requests.",
            "d) It is a class that holds the component's data and business logic."
        ],
        "answer": "b) It is a file that defines the structure and layout of a component's view."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 5,
        "question": "What is the purpose of 'FormsModule' in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to initialize data members and make API calls.",
            "c) It is used to subscribe to Observables and handle asynchronous operations.",
            "d) It is used to work with forms and form data in Angular."
        ],
        "answer": "d) It is used to work with forms and form data in Angular."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 6,
        "question": "What is the purpose of 'HttpClientModule' in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to initialize data members and make API calls.",
            "c) It is used to subscribe to Observables and handle asynchronous operations.",
            "d) It is used to create a new component instance."
        ],
        "answer": "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 7,
        "question": "In Angular, what is the purpose of 'ngIf' directive?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to conditionally render elements based on a boolean expression.",
            "b) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "c) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "d) It is used to subscribe to Observables and handle asynchronous operations."
        ],
        "answer": "a) It is used to conditionally render elements based on a boolean expression."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 8,
        "question": "What is the purpose of 'ngSwitch' directive in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to conditionally render elements based on multiple cases.",
            "c) It is used to subscribe to Observables and handle asynchronous operations.",
            "d) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically."
        ],
        "answer": "b) It is used to conditionally render elements based on multiple cases."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 9,
        "question": "In Angular, how do you bind a variable to an input element and update it in real-time?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) [value]",
            "b) (bind)",
            "c) (update)",
            "d) [(ngModel)]"
        ],
        "answer": "d) [(ngModel)]"
    },
    {
        "quesID": 10,
        "question": "Which Angular CLI command is used to generate a new component?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) ng new",
            "b) ng create",
            "c) ng generate component",
            "d) ng make component"
        ],
        "answer": "c) ng generate component"
    },
    {
        "quesID": 11,
        "question": "What is the purpose of 'ngClass' directive in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "c) It is used to conditionally apply CSS classes based on a condition.",
            "d) It is used to subscribe to Observables and handle asynchronous operations."
        ],
        "answer": "c) It is used to conditionally apply CSS classes based on a condition."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 12,
        "question": "What is Angular Interpolation?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is a way to bind data from the component to the view using curly braces {{}}.",
            "b) It is a service that handles HTTP requests.",
            "c) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "d) It is a method to handle asynchronous operations in Angular."
        ],
        "answer": "a) It is a way to bind data from the component to the view using curly braces {{}}."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 13,
        "question": "Which lifecycle hook is used to perform any action before a component is destroyed in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) ngOnInit",
            "b) ngOnDestroy",
            "c) ngDestroy",
            "d) ngOnChange"
        ],
        "answer": "b) ngOnDestroy"
    },
    {
        "quesID": 14,
        "question": "In Angular, what is the purpose of 'ngStyle' directive?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "b) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "c) It is used to conditionally apply inline CSS styles based on a condition.",
            "d) It is used to subscribe to Observables and handle asynchronous operations."
        ],
        "answer": "c) It is used to conditionally apply inline CSS styles based on a condition."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 15,
        "question": "What is Angular Router used for?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to create a new component instance.",
            "c) It is used to navigate between different views and pages.",
            "d) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically."
        ],
        "answer": "c) It is used to navigate between different views and pages."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 16,
        "question": "What is the purpose of 'ViewChild' decorator in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "c) It is used to inject a child component into a parent component.",
            "d) It is used to subscribe to Observables and handle asynchronous operations."
        ],
        "answer": "c) It is used to inject a child component into a parent component."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 17,
        "question": "In Angular, how do you create a two-way data binding?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) [value]",
            "b) (bind)",
            "c) (update)",
            "d) [(ngModel)]"
        ],
        "answer": "d) [(ngModel)]"
    },
    {
        "quesID": 18,
        "question": "What is the purpose of 'ngSubmit' directive in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "c) It is used to conditionally apply CSS classes based on a condition.",
            "d) It is used to handle form submission."
        ],
        "answer": "d) It is used to handle form submission."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 19,
        "question": "What is Angular CLI?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is a service that handles HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is a command-line interface tool used to develop, build, and test Angular applications.",
            "c) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "d) It is a way to bind data from the component to the view using curly braces {{}}."
        ],
        "answer": "b) It is a command-line interface tool used to develop, build, and test Angular applications."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 20,
        "question": "In Angular, what is the purpose of 'ngModel' directive?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "b) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "c) It is used to conditionally apply inline CSS styles based on a condition.",
            "d) It is used for two-way data binding between form elements and component variables."
        ],
        "answer": "d) It is used for two-way data binding between form elements and component variables."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 21,
        "question": "What is the purpose of 'ngIf' else block in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "c) It is used to conditionally render elements based on a boolean expression.",
            "d) It is used to render an alternate template if the 'ngIf' condition is false."
        ],
        "answer": "d) It is used to render an alternate template if the 'ngIf' condition is false."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 22,
        "question": "What is the purpose of 'ngClass' else block in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "c) It is used to apply an alternate set of CSS classes if the 'ngClass' condition is false.",
            "d) It is used to conditionally apply CSS classes based on a condition."
        ],
        "answer": "c) It is used to apply an alternate set of CSS classes if the 'ngClass' condition is false."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 23,
        "question": "What is the purpose of the 'async' pipe in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "b) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "c) It is used to subscribe to Observables and handle asynchronous operations.",
            "d) It is used to conditionally render elements based on a boolean expression."
        ],
        "answer": "c) It is used to subscribe to Observables and handle asynchronous operations."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 24,
        "question": "In Angular, what is the purpose of 'ngTemplateOutlet' directive?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to conditionally render elements based on a boolean expression.",
            "c) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "d) It is used to insert a template dynamically into the view."
        ],
        "answer": "d) It is used to insert a template dynamically into the view."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 25,
        "question": "What is Angular Dependency Injection?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is a way to handle HTTP requests in Angular.",
            "b) It is a mechanism to inject dependencies into a class or component.",
            "c) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "d) It is a method to handle asynchronous operations in Angular."
        ],
        "answer": "b) It is a mechanism to inject dependencies into a class or component."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 26,
        "question": "What is the purpose of the 'ngContent' directive in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to conditionally render elements based on a boolean expression.",
            "c) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "d) It is used to project content into a component's view from the parent component."
        ],
        "answer": "d) It is used to project content into a component's view from the parent component."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 27,
        "question": "What is the purpose of 'ngContainer' in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to conditionally render elements based on a boolean expression.",
            "c) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "d) It is used to group multiple elements and apply structural directives to them."
        ],
        "answer": "d) It is used to group multiple elements and apply structural directives to them."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 28,
        "question": "What is the purpose of 'ng-content' in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to conditionally render elements based on a boolean expression.",
            "c) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "d) It is used to project content into a component's view from the parent component."
        ],
        "answer": "d) It is used to project content into a component's view from the parent component."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 29,
        "question": "What is the purpose of 'ng-container' in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to conditionally render elements based on a boolean expression.",
            "c) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "d) It is used to group multiple elements and apply structural directives to them."
        ],
        "answer": "d) It is used to group multiple elements and apply structural directives to them."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 30,
        "question": "What is the purpose of 'trackBy' in Angular's ngFor?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to conditionally render elements based on a boolean expression.",
            "c) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "d) It is used to improve performance when rendering lists by providing a unique identifier for each item."
        ],
        "answer": "d) It is used to improve performance when rendering lists by providing a unique identifier for each item."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 31,
        "question": "What is the purpose of 'ngZone' in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to conditionally render elements based on a boolean expression.",
            "c) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "d) It is used to handle change detection and perform tasks outside of Angular's Zone."
        ],
        "answer": "d) It is used to handle change detection and perform tasks outside of Angular's Zone."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 32,
        "question": "In Angular, what is the purpose of 'ngZone.run()'?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to conditionally render elements based on a boolean expression.",
            "c) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "d) It is used to execute a function inside Angular's Zone."
        ],
        "answer": "d) It is used to execute a function inside Angular's Zone."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 33,
        "question": "What is the purpose of 'ChangeDetectionStrategy' in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to conditionally render elements based on a boolean expression.",
            "c) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "d) It is used to control when and how change detection is triggered for a component."
        ],
        "answer": "d) It is used to control when and how change detection is triggered for a component."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 34,
        "question": "In Angular, how do you communicate between parent and child components?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) Using 'ng-content' and 'ng-container'",
            "b) Using 'ngZone'",
            "c) Using 'Input' and 'Output' properties",
            "d) Using 'ngIf' and 'else' block"
        ],
        "answer": "c) Using 'Input' and 'Output' properties"
    },
    {
        "quesID": 35,
        "question": "What is the purpose of 'ngOnInit' method in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to initialize data members and make API calls.",
            "c) It is used to subscribe to Observables and handle asynchronous operations.",
            "d) It is used to create a new component instance."
        ],
        "answer": "b) It is used to initialize data members and make API calls."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 36,
        "question": "What is the purpose of 'ngOnChanges' method in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "c) It is used to conditionally apply CSS classes based on a condition.",
            "d) It is used to perform actions when the input properties of a component change."
        ],
        "answer": "d) It is used to perform actions when the input properties of a component change."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 37,
        "question": "In Angular, what is the purpose of 'ngOnDestroy' method?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "c) It is used to unsubscribe from Observables and perform cleanup tasks before a component is destroyed.",
            "d) It is used to perform actions when the input properties of a component change."
        ],
        "answer": "c) It is used to unsubscribe from Observables and perform cleanup tasks before a component is destroyed."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 38,
        "question": "What is Angular CLI command used to create a new Angular project?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) ng new",
            "b) ng create",
            "c) ng generate",
            "d) ng make"
        ],
        "answer": "a) ng new"
    },
    {
        "quesID": 39,
        "question": "In Angular, what is the purpose of 'ngStyle' directive?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to conditionally render elements based on a boolean expression.",
            "c) It is used to apply inline CSS styles based on a condition.",
            "d) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically."
        ],
        "answer": "c) It is used to apply inline CSS styles based on a condition."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 40,
        "question": "What is the purpose of 'ngClass' directive in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to conditionally render elements based on a boolean expression.",
            "c) It is used to apply CSS classes based on a condition.",
            "d) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically."
        ],
        "answer": "c) It is used to apply CSS classes based on a condition."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 41,
        "question": "What is Angular Router used for?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to create a new component instance.",
            "c) It is used to navigate between different views and pages.",
            "d) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically."
        ],
        "answer": "c) It is used to navigate between different views and pages."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 42,
        "question": "In Angular, what is the purpose of 'ngModel' directive?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "b) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "c) It is used to conditionally apply inline CSS styles based on a condition.",
            "d) It is used for two-way data binding between form elements and component variables."
        ],
        "answer": "d) It is used for two-way data binding between form elements and component variables."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 43,
        "question": "What is the purpose of 'ngSubmit' directive in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "c) It is used to conditionally apply CSS classes based on a condition.",
            "d) It is used to handle form submission."
        ],
        "answer": "d) It is used to handle form submission."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 44,
        "question": "What is Angular CLI?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is a service that handles HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is a command-line interface tool used to develop, build, and test Angular applications.",
            "c) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "d) It is a way to bind data from the component to the view using curly braces {{}}."
        ],
        "answer": "b) It is a command-line interface tool used to develop, build, and test Angular applications."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 45,
        "question": "In Angular, what is the purpose of 'ngIf' else block?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to conditionally render elements based on a boolean expression.",
            "c) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "d) It is used to render an alternate template if the 'ngIf' condition is false."
        ],
        "answer": "d) It is used to render an alternate template if the 'ngIf' condition is false."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 46,
        "question": "What is the purpose of 'ngSwitch' directive in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to conditionally render elements based on multiple cases.",
            "c) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "d) It is used to subscribe to Observables and handle asynchronous operations."
        ],
        "answer": "b) It is used to conditionally render elements based on multiple cases."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 47,
        "question": "In Angular, how do you bind a variable to an input element and update it in real-time?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) [value]",
            "b) (bind)",
            "c) (update)",
            "d) [(ngModel)]"
        ],
        "answer": "d) [(ngModel)]"
    },
    {
        "quesID": 48,
        "question": "Which Angular CLI command is used to generate a new component?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) ng new",
            "b) ng create",
            "c) ng generate component",
            "d) ng make component"
        ],
        "answer": "c) ng generate component"
    },
    {
        "quesID": 49,
        "question": "What is the purpose of 'ngClass' else block in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "c) It is used to apply an alternate set of CSS classes if the 'ngClass' condition is false.",
            "d) It is used to conditionally apply CSS classes based on a condition."
        ],
        "answer": "c) It is used to apply an alternate set of CSS classes if the 'ngClass' condition is false."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 50,
        "question": "What is Angular Interpolation?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is a way to bind data from the component to the view using curly braces {{}}.",
            "b) It is a service that handles HTTP requests.",
            "c) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "d) It is a method to handle asynchronous operations in Angular."
        ],
        "answer": "a) It is a way to bind data from the component to the view using curly braces {{}}."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 51,
        "question": "Which lifecycle hook is used to perform any action before a component is destroyed in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) ngOnInit",
            "b) ngOnDestroy",
            "c) ngDestroy",
            "d) ngOnChange"
        ],
        "answer": "b) ngOnDestroy"
    },
    {
        "quesID": 52,
        "question": "In Angular, what is the purpose of 'ngIf' directive?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "c) It is used to conditionally render elements based on a boolean expression.",
            "d) It is used to subscribe to Observables and handle asynchronous operations."
        ],
        "answer": "c) It is used to conditionally render elements based on a boolean expression."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 53,
        "question": "What is the purpose of 'ngSwitch' directive in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to conditionally render elements based on multiple cases.",
            "c) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "d) It is used to subscribe to Observables and handle asynchronous operations."
        ],
        "answer": "b) It is used to conditionally render elements based on multiple cases."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 54,
        "question": "In Angular, how do you bind a variable to an input element and update it in real-time?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) [value]",
            "b) (bind)",
            "c) (update)",
            "d) [(ngModel)]"
        ],
        "answer": "d) [(ngModel)]"
    },
    {
        "quesID": 55,
        "question": "Which Angular CLI command is used to generate a new component?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) ng new",
            "b) ng create",
            "c) ng generate component",
            "d) ng make component"
        ],
        "answer": "c) ng generate component"
    },
    {
        "quesID": 56,
        "question": "What is the purpose of 'ngClass' else block in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "c) It is used to apply an alternate set of CSS classes if the 'ngClass' condition is false.",
            "d) It is used to conditionally apply CSS classes based on a condition."
        ],
        "answer": "c) It is used to apply an alternate set of CSS classes if the 'ngClass' condition is false."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 57,
        "question": "What is Angular Interpolation?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is a way to bind data from the component to the view using curly braces {{}}.",
            "b) It is a service that handles HTTP requests.",
            "c) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "d) It is a method to handle asynchronous operations in Angular."
        ],
        "answer": "a) It is a way to bind data from the component to the view using curly braces {{}}."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 58,
        "question": "Which lifecycle hook is used to perform any action before a component is destroyed in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) ngOnInit",
            "b) ngOnDestroy",
            "c) ngDestroy",
            "d) ngOnChange"
        ],
        "answer": "b) ngOnDestroy"
    },
    {
        "quesID": 59,
        "question": "In Angular, what is the purpose of 'ngIf' directive?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "c) It is used to conditionally render elements based on a boolean expression.",
            "d) It is used to subscribe to Observables and handle asynchronous operations."
        ],
        "answer": "c) It is used to conditionally render elements based on a boolean expression."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 60,
        "question": "What is the purpose of 'ngSwitch' directive in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to conditionally render elements based on multiple cases.",
            "c) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "d) It is used to subscribe to Observables and handle asynchronous operations."
        ],
        "answer": "b) It is used to conditionally render elements based on multiple cases."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 61,
        "question": "In Angular, how do you bind a variable to an input element and update it in real-time?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) [value]",
            "b) (bind)",
            "c) (update)",
            "d) [(ngModel)]"
        ],
        "answer": "d) [(ngModel)]"
    },
    {
        "quesID": 62,
        "question": "Which Angular CLI command is used to generate a new component?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) ng new",
            "b) ng create",
            "c) ng generate component",
            "d) ng make component"
        ],
        "answer": "c) ng generate component"
    },
    {
        "quesID": 63,
        "question": "What is the purpose of 'ngClass' else block in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "c) It is used to apply an alternate set of CSS classes if the 'ngClass' condition is false.",
            "d) It is used to conditionally apply CSS classes based on a condition."
        ],
        "answer": "c) It is used to apply an alternate set of CSS classes if the 'ngClass' condition is false."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 64,
        "question": "What is Angular Interpolation?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is a way to bind data from the component to the view using curly braces {{}}.",
            "b) It is a service that handles HTTP requests.",
            "c) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "d) It is a method to handle asynchronous operations in Angular."
        ],
        "answer": "a) It is a way to bind data from the component to the view using curly braces {{}}."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 65,
        "question": "Which lifecycle hook is used to perform any action before a component is destroyed in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) ngOnInit",
            "b) ngOnDestroy",
            "c) ngDestroy",
            "d) ngOnChange"
        ],
        "answer": "b) ngOnDestroy"
    },
    {
        "quesID": 66,
        "question": "In Angular, what is the purpose of 'ngIf' directive?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "c) It is used to conditionally render elements based on a boolean expression.",
            "d) It is used to subscribe to Observables and handle asynchronous operations."
        ],
        "answer": "c) It is used to conditionally render elements based on a boolean expression."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 67,
        "question": "What is the purpose of 'ngSwitch' directive in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to conditionally render elements based on multiple cases.",
            "c) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "d) It is used to subscribe to Observables and handle asynchronous operations."
        ],
        "answer": "b) It is used to conditionally render elements based on multiple cases."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 68,
        "question": "In Angular, how do you bind a variable to an input element and update it in real-time?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) [value]",
            "b) (bind)",
            "c) (update)",
            "d) [(ngModel)]"
        ],
        "answer": "d) [(ngModel)]"
    },
    {
        "quesID": 69,
        "question": "Which Angular CLI command is used to generate a new component?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) ng new",
            "b) ng create",
            "c) ng generate component",
            "d) ng make component"
        ],
        "answer": "c) ng generate component"
    },
    {
        "quesID": 70,
        "question": "What is the purpose of 'ngClass' else block in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "c) It is used to apply an alternate set of CSS classes if the 'ngClass' condition is false.",
            "d) It is used to conditionally apply CSS classes based on a condition."
        ],
        "answer": "c) It is used to apply an alternate set of CSS classes if the 'ngClass' condition is false."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 71,
        "question": "What is Angular Interpolation?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is a way to bind data from the component to the view using curly braces {{}}.",
            "b) It is a service that handles HTTP requests.",
            "c) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "d) It is a method to handle asynchronous operations in Angular."
        ],
        "answer": "a) It is a way to bind data from the component to the view using curly braces {{}}."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 72,
        "question": "Which lifecycle hook is used to perform any action before a component is destroyed in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) ngOnInit",
            "b) ngOnDestroy",
            "c) ngDestroy",
            "d) ngOnChange"
        ],
        "answer": "b) ngOnDestroy"
    },
    {
        "quesID": 73,
        "question": "In Angular, what is the purpose of 'ngIf' directive?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "c) It is used to conditionally render elements based on a boolean expression.",
            "d) It is used to subscribe to Observables and handle asynchronous operations."
        ],
        "answer": "c) It is used to conditionally render elements based on a boolean expression."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 74,
        "question": "What is the purpose of 'ngSwitch' directive in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to conditionally render elements based on multiple cases.",
            "c) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "d) It is used to subscribe to Observables and handle asynchronous operations."
        ],
        "answer": "b) It is used to conditionally render elements based on multiple cases."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 75,
        "question": "In Angular, how do you bind a variable to an input element and update it in real-time?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) [value]",
            "b) (bind)",
            "c) (update)",
            "d) [(ngModel)]"
        ],
        "answer": "d) [(ngModel)]"
    },
    {
        "quesID": 76,
        "question": "Which Angular CLI command is used to generate a new component?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) ng new",
            "b) ng create",
            "c) ng generate component",
            "d) ng make component"
        ],
        "answer": "c) ng generate component"
    },
    {
        "quesID": 77,
        "question": "What is the purpose of 'ngClass' else block in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "c) It is used to apply an alternate set of CSS classes if the 'ngClass' condition is false.",
            "d) It is used to conditionally apply CSS classes based on a condition."
        ],
        "answer": "c) It is used to apply an alternate set of CSS classes if the 'ngClass' condition is false."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 78,
        "question": "What is Angular Interpolation?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is a way to bind data from the component to the view using curly braces {{}}.",
            "b) It is a service that handles HTTP requests.",
            "c) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "d) It is a method to handle asynchronous operations in Angular."
        ],
        "answer": "a) It is a way to bind data from the component to the view using curly braces {{}}."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 79,
        "question": "Which lifecycle hook is used to perform any action before a component is destroyed in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) ngOnInit",
            "b) ngOnDestroy",
            "c) ngDestroy",
            "d) ngOnChange"
        ],
        "answer": "b) ngOnDestroy"
    },
    {
        "quesID": 80,
        "question": "In Angular, what is the purpose of 'ngIf' directive?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "c) It is used to conditionally render elements based on a boolean expression.",
            "d) It is used to subscribe to Observables and handle asynchronous operations."
        ],
        "answer": "c) It is used to conditionally render elements based on a boolean expression."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 81,
        "question": "What is the purpose of 'ngSwitch' directive in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to conditionally render elements based on multiple cases.",
            "c) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "d) It is used to subscribe to Observables and handle asynchronous operations."
        ],
        "answer": "b) It is used to conditionally render elements based on multiple cases."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 82,
        "question": "In Angular, how do you bind a variable to an input element and update it in real-time?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) [value]",
            "b) (bind)",
            "c) (update)",
            "d) [(ngModel)]"
        ],
        "answer": "d) [(ngModel)]"
    },
    {
        "quesID": 83,
        "question": "Which Angular CLI command is used to generate a new component?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) ng new",
            "b) ng create",
            "c) ng generate component",
            "d) ng make component"
        ],
        "answer": "c) ng generate component"
    },
    {
        "quesID": 84,
        "question": "What is the purpose of 'ngClass' else block in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "c) It is used to apply an alternate set of CSS classes if the 'ngClass' condition is false.",
            "d) It is used to conditionally apply CSS classes based on a condition."
        ],
        "answer": "c) It is used to apply an alternate set of CSS classes if the 'ngClass' condition is false."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 85,
        "question": "What is Angular Interpolation?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is a way to bind data from the component to the view using curly braces {{}}.",
            "b) It is a service that handles HTTP requests.",
            "c) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "d) It is a method to handle asynchronous operations in Angular."
        ],
        "answer": "a) It is a way to bind data from the component to the view using curly braces {{}}."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 86,
        "question": "Which lifecycle hook is used to perform any action before a component is destroyed in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) ngOnInit",
            "b) ngOnDestroy",
            "c) ngDestroy",
            "d) ngOnChange"
        ],
        "answer": "b) ngOnDestroy"
    },
    {
        "quesID": 87,
        "question": "In Angular, what is the purpose of 'ngIf' directive?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "c) It is used to conditionally render elements based on a boolean expression.",
            "d) It is used to subscribe to Observables and handle asynchronous operations."
        ],
        "answer": "c) It is used to conditionally render elements based on a boolean expression."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 88,
        "question": "What is the purpose of 'ngSwitch' directive in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
       
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "c) It is used to conditionally render elements based on a boolean expression.",
            "d) It is used to subscribe to Observables and handle asynchronous operations."
        ],
        "answer": "c) It is used to conditionally render elements based on a boolean expression."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 89,
        "question": "What is the purpose of 'ngSwitch' directive in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to conditionally render elements based on multiple cases.",
            "c) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "d) It is used to subscribe to Observables and handle asynchronous operations."
        ],
        "answer": "b) It is used to conditionally render elements based on multiple cases."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 90,
        "question": "In Angular, how do you bind a variable to an input element and update it in real-time?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) [value]",
            "b) (bind)",
            "c) (update)",
            "d) [(ngModel)]"
        ],
        "answer": "d) [(ngModel)]"
    },
    {
        "quesID": 91,
        "question": "Which Angular CLI command is used to generate a new component?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) ng new",
            "b) ng create",
            "c) ng generate component",
            "d) ng make component"
        ],
        "answer": "c) ng generate component"
    },
    {
        "quesID": 92,
        "question": "What is the purpose of 'ngClass' else block in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "c) It is used to apply an alternate set of CSS classes if the 'ngClass' condition is false.",
            "d) It is used to conditionally apply CSS classes based on a condition."
        ],
        "answer": "c) It is used to apply an alternate set of CSS classes if the 'ngClass' condition is false."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 93,
        "question": "What is Angular Interpolation?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is a way to bind data from the component to the view using curly braces {{}}.",
            "b) It is a service that handles HTTP requests.",
            "c) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "d) It is a method to handle asynchronous operations in Angular."
        ],
        "answer": "a) It is a way to bind data from the component to the view using curly braces {{}}."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 94,
        "question": "Which lifecycle hook is used to perform any action before a component is destroyed in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) ngOnInit",
            "b) ngOnDestroy",
            "c) ngDestroy",
            "d) ngOnChange"
        ],
        "answer": "b) ngOnDestroy"
    },
    {
        "quesID": 95,
        "question": "In Angular, what is the purpose of 'ngIf' directive?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "c) It is used to conditionally render elements based on a boolean expression.",
            "d) It is used to subscribe to Observables and handle asynchronous operations."
        ],
        "answer": "c) It is used to conditionally render elements based on a boolean expression."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 96,
        "question": "What is the purpose of 'ngSwitch' directive in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to conditionally render elements based on multiple cases.",
            "c) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "d) It is used to subscribe to Observables and handle asynchronous operations."
        ],
        "answer": "b) It is used to conditionally render elements based on multiple cases."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 97,
        "question": "In Angular, how do you bind a variable to an input element and update it in real-time?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) [value]",
            "b) (bind)",
            "c) (update)",
            "d) [(ngModel)]"
        ],
        "answer": "d) [(ngModel)]"
    },
    {
        "quesID": 98,
        "question": "Which Angular CLI command is used to generate a new component?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) ng new",
            "b) ng create",
            "c) ng generate component",
            "d) ng make component"
        ],
        "answer": "c) ng generate component"
    },
    {
        "quesID": 99,
        "question": "What is the purpose of 'ngClass' else block in Angular?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to handle HTTP requests.",
            "b) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "c) It is used to apply an alternate set of CSS classes if the 'ngClass' condition is false.",
            "d) It is used to conditionally apply CSS classes based on a condition."
        ],
        "answer": "c) It is used to apply an alternate set of CSS classes if the 'ngClass' condition is false."
    },
    {
        "quesID": 100,
        "question": "What is Angular Interpolation?",
        "imageName": "",
        "options": [
            "a) It is a way to bind data from the component to the view using curly braces {{}}.",
            "b) It is a service that handles HTTP requests.",
            "c) It is used to loop through an array and render elements dynamically.",
            "d) It is a method to handle asynchronous operations in Angular."
        ],
        "answer": "a) It is a way to bind data from the component to the view using curly braces {{}}."
    }
]
